dmusic.com 2006-06-15

# DMusic.com | for indie musicians and fans | Free MP3 music downloads

**Overview**

Please read this statement to understand how we will treat the personal information that you give to us. Our privacy procedures include the following: 

  * We disclose our privacy practices and procedures in this document. 
  * We do not sell or rent your personally identifiable information to third parties for marketing purposes without providing you with a choice to opt out from such disclosure, which you can exercise during registration or by editing your Member Profile at any time. 
  * We allow users to opt out at any time from receiving e-mail messages from us or from having information shared with third parties, including selected sponsors or business partners. 
  * We allow you to access your users profiles and change information as they deem necessary. 

Since this policy may change over time as we modify or expand our service, we suggest that you check back from time to time in order to understand how we treat your information. Your use of the Dmusic Website constitutes your agreement to the terms of this privacy policy. If we decide to materially change our privacy policy, we will prominently post those changes on this page prior to the change and provide you an opportunity to opt-out, so that you are always aware of what personal information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we disclose it. Your continued use of the Dmusic Website constitutes your agreement to any such changes. 

**What Personally Identifiable Information of yours is collected**

Information collected online is often defined as being either anonymous or personally identifiable: 

  1. "Anonymous Information" refers to information that cannot be tied back to a specific individual. For instance, we may know that 10,000 people visit this Privacy Policy today, but we do not necessarily know their names, where they live, or their date of birth.
  2. "Personally Identifiable Information" or "PII" refers to information that tells us specifically who you are, such as your name, phone number, or postal address. 

The amount of Personally Identifiable Information that you choose to disclose to us is completely up to you. In our effort to provide personalization and opportunities for prizes and services, we may at times ask you to submit information such as your name or email address, or to share your interests and hobbies with us. The type of information may include: 

  * Credit card information to process your request for products, programs, or services. 
  * Information you provide when registering to receive goods or services from one or more of our partners. 
  * Information you provide when entering into a contest, sweepstakes or promotion sponsored by Dmusic and/or one of our partners. 
  * Information you provide when filling out a user survey. 
  * Information you provide if you contact customer service. 
  * Data related to the areas of Dmusic that you visit and how often you visit those areas. This includes co-branded sections of Dmusic that are part of our overall service. 

You never have to answer any questions, and you can decline this exchange of information at any time. However, if you should choose to withhold requested information, we may not be able to provide you with some of the services dependent upon the collection of this information, such as a personalized start page a personalized stock portfolio, a sweepstakes entry, or the purchase and shipment of products and prizes to people who visit our network. 

When you surf the Internet, your Internet browser (such as Netscape Navigator(r) or Microsoft Internet Explorer) automatically transmits some information to Dmusic every time you access content on one of our sites. Examples of such information include the URL of the Web page you were just on (known as the "Refer"), the IP (or Internet Protocol) address of the computer you are using, or the browser version you are using to access our site. All of this information may be collected by Dmusic and used to help improve our offerings to you. 

We use third-party advertising cookies to serve some of the ads that appear when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, e-mail address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites to provide advertisements about goods or services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, we encourage you to contact those companies directly or the Network Advertising Initiative at www.networkadvertising.org for further information on the policies of major third party ad servers and how to opt-out.. 

_Children Under the Age of 13_

As a matter of policy, Dmusic does not knowingly collect PII from anyone under the age of 13 or allow such persons to register. If you are a person under age 13 who registered on the Dmusic Website prior to the date of transfer, no data pertaining to you (including any PII) has been provided to us. 

For information on how to protect the privacy and safety of children online, we recommend that you visit the Parents and Children portion of the TRUSTe site, which contains information and links to other resources on this subject.

**How the information is used**

We use the personal information you supply us, including your registration data, to enhance our services, fulfill your requests for products, programs, or services, personalize your experience and provide you or permit others to provide you with special offers we think you will find valuable. We also use other information obtained from user site traffic patterns to better provide you with a personalized experience and special advertising offers and promotions. We view personalized advertising as beneficial to our users. 

We also use your registration data information in connection with the sweepstakes and other promotions in order to track your progress, to notify you if you are a winner and to ensure that we comply with the applicable laws. 

Dmusic uses the information described above to do, among other things, the following: 

  * Personalize and enhance the Dmusic site and service such as providing you with your personalized weather, horoscope, and advertisements we believe will be of interest to you. 
  * Send PII about Dmusic and its site features, prizes and special offers, unless you have opted out of receiving these types of communications. 
  * Send you advertising from third parties including selected and trusted Dmusic partners, unless you have opted out of receiving these types of communications. 
  * Provide your PII to selected 3rd parties unless you have opted not to permit such sharing. 
  * Provide you with advertising and other promotional offers that we believe will be of interest to you. 
  * Contact users for feedback regarding Dmusic and Dmusic's partners via email surveys. 

We may also use the information we collect to develop summary reports for our advertisers. An example of a summary report might be "100,000 people clicked on this link and of those people, 35% were registered users above the age of 25." We provide this information to assist our advertisers in determining how to promote their products. We do not tell our advertisers who it was that saw or clicked on their advertisements unless you have told us this is acceptable. 

Unless you have opted out of receiving special offers, emails or other communications from selected third parties, we also may provide a report to our advertiser which tells them who responded to a particular offer. For example, we might send you an email, launch a new window within your internet browser, or send you other advertisements in electronic form which offer you a discount on a particular good or service. If you click on that e-mail or advertisement or accept an offer or discount contained therein, we may provide the advertiser with the information necessary to provide you with that discount or offer. 

Dmusic may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide Personally Identifiable Information to appropriate governmental authorities. If requested by law enforcement or judicial authorities, we will provide this information upon receipt of the appropriate documentation. Dmusic may also provide information to law enforcement to protect its property and the health and safety of individual as permitted by statute. 

Other companies that place advertising on our site may collect information about you when you view or click on their advertising or content through the use of cookies (using the same techniques as described above). Due to the way the Internet technically operates, we cannot control this collection of information. As the consumer you should contact these advertisers or content providers that place information on the Dmusic Website directly if you have any questions about their use of the information they potentially collect. 

Information that you provide while using products such as Dmusic Message Boards and Dmusic Chat is available for all to see. Discretion should be used in entering Personally Identifiable Information within such forums, as it may be collected by third parties. Dmusic does not actively associate the message content entered by our users in Dmusic Message Boards, or Dmusic Chat products with those users' registration information. Our server computers will retain this information, however; and it is potentially available for distribution to third parties - most obviously law-enforcement agencies acting under subpoena power, per the terms of this section of our Privacy Policy. We do not use this information to target any advertising to our users, nor is it ever willingly distributed to any third party, such as an advertiser, except if subpoenaed. 

**With whom the information may be shared**

In general, Dmusic does not disclose your personally identifiable information to any third party without first providing you with an opportunity to opt out, except in special situations described below, such as to comply with the law or administer the site. Unless you have opted out, Dmusic may make your personally identifiable information available to selected companies. You can elect to opt-out at anytime by updating the preferences in your Member Profile. You can also elect not to use certain services or participate in certain promotions if you do not want your information shared with the third parties who are sponsoring or administering such promotions. In the event that all or substantially all of Dmusic's stock and/or assets are transferred or sold to another entity, Dmusic may transfer personally identifiable information to the acquiring entity. If, as a result of such a business transition, your personally identifiable information will be used in a materially different manner, you will be given choice consistent with our policy regarding notification of changes. 

Dmusic may disclose your personally identifiable information if we believe in good faith that we are required to do so in order to comply with applicable law, a subpoena, or other legal process. Dmusic may also disclose personally identifiable information when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our Terms of Service or to protect the safety of our users and the public or under confidentiality agreements with certain third parties which assist us in developing, operating and maintaining Dmusic. 

**What happens when you leave Dmusic to go to other sites**

Dmusic does not control the information collection and distribution policies on Internet domains other than those internet domains that are under the control of Dmusic itself. When you are on the Dmusic Website, you may be directed to other sites that are beyond our control. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement or an Dmusic Website search result, the "click" may take you off the Dmusic Website site. These other sites may independently collect data, solicit personal information, or send their own cookies to you. Dmusic is not responsible for any use of the information including click-stream data, that you may create when using such third party sites. 

We also offer you access to "co-branded" services that are jointly provided by Dmusic and selected companies. In many cases, these co-branded services will contain Dmusic Website branding, but may not be hosted by Dmusic. You may notice that you are on a co-branded site if the pages say "provided by", if standard Dmusic branding is not displayed on the top of the page, or if you are asked to subscribe for any service or provide additional information. In such cases, if you use the co-branded service, Dmusic may be entitled to receive information about what you do when using that service. If you elect to provide additional personal information using a co-branded service, the information you provide may be shared or jointly retained by the provider of that service in accordance with that provider's privacy policies and terms of service. We encourage you to read the privacy polices of these other companies and to contact these companies directly if you have any questions about their use of this information. When you are using a co-branded service, we will attempt to make sure that there is a link to the service provider's applicable privacy policies and terms of service. 

We may also offer you access to software products which are installed on an individual user's computer. Dmusic software applications automatically communicate over the Internet with our servers and, in order to provide you with Dmusic Website services, may convey to Dmusic certain information regarding your activities at destinations other than the Dmusic Website, such as the URL of sites you visit. Dmusic software applications may also upgrade their functionalities from time to time, and some of these functionalities may expand the scope of the information that is communicated to Dmusic Website's servers. 

**What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of personal information**

You can always choose whether or not to disclose personally identifiable information and that choice will not prevent you from using the Dmusic Website. Please note, however if you should choose to withhold requested information, we may not be able to provide you with some of the services dependent upon the collection of this information, such as a personalized start page a personalized stock portfolio, a sweepstakes entry, or the purchase and shipment of products and prizes. 

You can choose at anytime to opt out of receiving emails from Dmusic or from having your personally identifiable information shared with selected companies. If you want to opt out, you can do so by editing your preferences with respect to email or the sharing of information. If you elect to "opt out" we will not, as applicable, share your personal information with third parties or send you emails. However, we may continue to use your personal information for internal purposes, to conduct sweepstakes and promotions, to enhance your user experience or as necessary to administer the site or comply with applicable law. 

We reserve the right to send a one-time registration confirmation email, and infrequent Service Alert messages to users to inform them of specific changes that may impact their ability to use a service they have previously signed up for, regardless of email contact opt-in status. An example of a Service Alert message would be notification of the impending closing of an account that is believed to be abandoned. And finally, we also reserve the right to contact you if compelled to do so as part of a legal proceeding or if there has been a violation of our Terms of Service. Dmusic is retaining these rights because in limited cases we feel that we may need the right to contact you as a matter of law or regarding matters which will be important to you. These rights do not allow us to contact you to market a new or existing service if you have asked us not to do so, and issuance of these types of communications are rare. 

_Children Ages 13-17_

We will not share the PII of users who are 13 to 17 years old with any third party - even if that user gave us permission to do so during registration - except in cases where the information is being shared with a nonprofit organization that offers bona fide outreach and support services to children. In cases where minors have volunteered information in the context of a peer counseling or mentoring environment on the Dmusic Website, this information will be shared with that nonprofit organization. As reflected in this Privacy Policy, we will provide PII about our users age 13-17 to law enforcement or judicial authorities upon request and receipt of proper documentation. Additionally, if we believe that Dmusic property or an individual's safety or security is at risk, we will provide this information to proper court or law enforcement agencies. 

Although Dmusic will not share the PII of users who are 13-17 years old with any third party, the Dmusic Website includes co-branded web properties, sponsor pages and links to other sites where you may be offered an opportunity to provide PII directly to a third party. If you elect to provide such information, we recommend that you review the privacy practices of that party. For more information on co-branded sites, see the section entitled "What happens when you leave Dmusic to go to other sites", above. 

**What kind of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under the company's control**

Dmusic operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary, and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our users. Even your registration account password is encrypted before it is sent to our computers. Any other particularly sensitive information, such as a customer's credit card number collected for a commerce transaction, is also encrypted prior to transmission. 

Dmusic takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with our Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you use these services at your own risk. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Dmusic will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. You the consumer are ultimately responsible for the security of your Dmusic Member Name and password.
